SNEHAL CHANDANE

OPTOMETRIST

If not at work you will find me in nature.



2 84

8424994919



snehalchandane19@gmail.com



A804, Renuka Residency, Katraj-Kondhva road, Pune

PROFILE

Independent optometrist with over 5.6 years of experience performing eye examinations along with expertise in handling and counseling the customers according to their needs. Skillful in preparing prescriptions for contact lenses and eyeglasses, maintaining strong commitment to accuracy. Versed at forging and cultivating productive relationships with clients, achieving high levels of satisfaction, retention and refferals.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR IN OPTOMETRY

- laxmi College of Optometry, Panvel
- 2013-2017

SECONDARY SCHOOL

- V. K. Mahavidyalay, Panvel
- 2011-2013

SKILLS

- · Contact lenses and eyeglass fitting
- Patient counseling
- Counter sales
- Problem-Solving approach
- Computer Literacy
- Attention to details
- Strong Communication

AWARDS&CITATIONS

- Awarded as Best Optometrist in Gangar Eyenation - 2019
- Selection of final year research work in World Congress of Optometry and All India Optometry Conference for oral and poster presentation in 2018

Interests

- Traveling
- Reading Fictional
- Music
- Gardening

References

- Rashmi Kanojiya: Professional Services
 Manager-CooperVision, India.
- Kavitha Pallery: Assistant professor and Course Co-ordinator, Department of Optometry DY Patil University.

EXPERIENCE

CONSULTANT OPTOMETRIST

Gangar Eyenation Pvt. Ltd.

2019 - Present

- Primarily worked as consultant Optometrist, prescribing corrective eye glasses and contact lenses to align with patients diagnosis.
- Fitting monofocal and multifocal soft contact lenses independently to patients according to their vision needs.
- Managing customers and their vision needs by suggesting appropriate eye product and handling troubleshootings.
- · Managing inventory stock for contact lenses and solutions.
- · Checking contact lens product availability for customers.

OPTOMETRIST

Lawrence and Mayo

2017-2019

- Worked as Optometrist, prescribing corrective eye glasses and contact lenses to align with patients diagnosis.
- Fitting monofocal and multifocal soft contact lenses independently to patients according to their needs.
- Managing customers and their vision needs by suggesting appropriate eye product and handling troubleshootings.
- · Managing inventory stocks.

INTERN OPTOMETRIST

Laxmi Eye Institute, Panvel

2016 - 2017

- Learned to performed various eye procedures and assisted for OT with residential doctors
- Assisted with dilating patients by using eye medications directed by ophthalmologist.
- Travelled for eye camps to perform various eye examinations voluntarily .

OTHER PROFESSIONAL ROLES

- Finance director (FD) in Rotaract club of LCO 2014-15
- · Club service director in Rotaract club of LCO 2015-16
- · Cultural head in students committee of LCO 2015-16